Welcome back to another video. We're here
with episode eight, 10 questions with a millionaire.
We're going to be linking with Mike Kessner here
in Austin, Texas. Ask him a couple of questions
on basically how he became successful. Hopefully you
have a good time doing it as well. Yeah.
Looking forward to it. Getting some expertise
from Mike. Super successful guy. So we're going
to get right into it. Mike, how you
doing? What's going on, Jack? How you doing, buddy?
Come on in. Good to see you. How you
doing, buddy? Good. Awesome. Yeah. So we just got,
we got like a couple of questions for you.
Obviously we kind of met in kind of an interesting
way. Pretty much we were out doing
street interviews for hard knocks, just trying to
find answers for, you know, younger people starting
out in the real world and ended up
running into you. And we did an interview. I
believe like the big question that we had asked
you that had gone kind of crazy viral on
the channel was what industry is the best to get
wealthy? And one of the answers you
said was private equity. It went crazy viral.
Over, I think well over 2 million views. Yeah. Well,
I got a funny update to that. So now my
son left his job in consulting and
is now at a large private equity firm.
And he's now a CEO of a company called, you
know, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the,
New York. Amazing. And my son-in-law left
investment banking and has now started a
private equity firm. So that's kind of
weird. There's very little chance. They probably didn't
even watch the clip, but it's just serendipitous.
Like, Oh, that's kind of weird. I said that.
And all my insurance buddy said, Oh, thanks a
lot. Don't you want people to get into insurance? I
said, no, it's just my honest answer. What career
did you originally go into out of high school and
college? Like kind of, where did you go from there
to get to where you are today? So I went to
LSU many years ago, thought I was going to
be a baseball player. Ended up sitting on the bench,
learned how to chew tobacco. They're transferred
to university of Denver. Ever since I transferred
LSU has been like a top 10 team. I guess
when I left, they became good. And then after college
first job, I think I was a headhunter. I quit
after a month because I, it was cold. I didn't
like getting up at six in the morning, taking
the train downtown Chicago. So I had to establish a
little more grit in my life and I didn't have it
then that ended quickly. Then I got a job with a
large company and transferred to,
and moved to St. Louis, which was great. I learned
a lot. It was good experience. I met my wife in
St. Louis 34 years ago. So I'll always be happy
and think highly of St. Louis. Then I wanted to
move home because my mom was a widow and I
kind of felt guilty. Ended up getting in the insurance
business. I've been in the insurance business for over
30 years. I was a producer. I didn't know
what I was doing for the first three or four years,
but I kind of always knew that if I just hung out
with authentic, good, high energy people, they
were eventually going to be successful. And then
I was like, I'm going to be successful if I kind
of play the long game and it worked out. So I did
that for 25, you know, probably over 25 years, met
a youngster, a young guy who's a CEO of an
insurance firm five years ago, roughly, and thought my
old firm would, we'd grown to be a large,
you know, firm, 2000 people, private equity roll
up, thought we'd purchase him and just became
friends. A year later, went to dinner with him and
my partner and myself, and he made us an offer.
We couldn't refuse. And it's been the most enjoyable
three and a half years of my career in
the insurance industry. Just kind
of coaching all the youngsters,
leaving a legacy. What exactly has
been your best and worst financial decision?
Best one might've been pre-pandemic. I was
just on an airplane reading about Nautilus,
which when I was a kid, it was like
the first gym, Nautilus machines. I was just reading about
it pre-pandemic by like a month. I go, they own
like a piece of Schwinn and some of these other
companies. So I poured some money into Nautilus,
pure luck. Then the pandemic happened. I poured
more money into it, figuring, well, people are going
to be stuck at home. It seems like they're
going to buy this stuff. That was the best. The
worst would be either Coinbase. So I gave a lot
of that, those winnings.
I would say Coinbase back, although I'm still holding
on. I would also say our home that we
raised the kids in. We were there for 20 plus
years. I think I'm the only person that was in
a house for 20 years that broke even.
I wouldn't trade anything in the world though. Incredible
memories. It was a beautiful house,
good neighborhood. So nothing but good memories.
And just, I guess the timing when we moved
wasn't perfect. So I would say that and Coinbase,
but Coinbase, I'm still fingers
crossed that that'll be okay.
I want to circle back to a question that we
asked you a very long time ago and your answer might
have changed a little bit, but what
industry would you like to be in?
What industry do you really think people need
to be looking to get into when they're starting
their career in today's day and age in 2023?
And I am not an expert in this industry,
but I would say data scientists. That would be
an industry that I would look at. I know for
our insurance firm, that's an area we want
to grow greatly. Have some young studs crunch all
the data and come to the old guys like me
and say, hey, this is trending, that's trending. So kind of
like Moneyball, which I know
is one of your favorites. Absolutely.
Yeah. It's kind of along those lines. Yeah.
But you say analytics is massive now for companies.
Analytics and any version of analytics I think.
And before we change spots, I just wanted
to ask, maybe talk about insurance just a little
bit, since you're in there. What advice would
you have to somebody wanting to go into the
insurance industry? I would say advice to if you're
going into the insurance industry or I would say
any sales position, you'd want to be at a place
where you're on a team because it's lonely to be
in sales, a lot of sales companies or you're on an
island. So to me, it's like try and make
it like sports. If you can't be a professional athlete
and you're in sales, try and make it like
sports. If you can't be a professional athlete and you're
in sales, try and make it like sports. And if
you can't make it like sports, try and make it like
a professional athlete and you're in sales. Just make
sure that you're in a team and you're working
be on a team that gets along and is really
a team. So when you win, it's fucking fun to celebrate.
And when you lose, you know, blame each other
and blame, blame the prospective client. So I think
team selling is huge. I'm going to kind of follow
up with you since we're kind of on the topic of
sales now, but what is your secret to sales when
you're on a call and you're trying to close a
deal? So one secret is they don't let me on
the calls anymore. I run sales for our company. So
we have like 25 sales folks and five
or six different teams with specialized verticals. So
I am rarely on the calls anymore. I'm just
pretty much coaching on strategy. So some of our sales
folks, they're technically brilliant. They're likable.
They're personable. They care about the
clients and they have very, very creative solutions that
most of the folks in our industry just don't
have because they're not as intelligent as
our teams. What do you implement throughout your
company to really stand out against competition that
kind of sells you guys over other companies?
Everyone.
Everyone at our firm, if you're in sales, you're
on a team and then you have a specialty. Our
specialties are private equity. So we have like
10 people that could go to a private equity
conference and they could talk about private equity
almost as much as the private equity folks.
So that's important. We have a hospitality team. So
they go to a hotel resort conferences and they
know that business. We have a construction team.
We have a team that focuses on restaurants. Team
ensures like 800 restaurants throughout the country.
Like if you own restaurants and I
could talk to you about restaurants and,
hey, these five clients of mine, they're really,
really good at dealing with these retention headaches
at their restaurant or they're starting to use this
company to do the paving, whatever. So it's a secret
sauce also to really know how to talk the talk
versus just being that generalist.
What has been the book that has been the most impactful
in your life that has led to the biggest change or
influence for you?
I would say and I read a boatload of books and now
I listen to books on occasion as well. So I probably read or
listen to three to five books a month. I'm embarrassed to
say the one that was most impactful was Don't Sweat the
Small Stuff. It's all small stuff. You know, I could say,
oh, it's Exodus or it's the big fellow or Boys in the
Boat, which is a great book about teamwork. But Don't
Sweat the Small Stuff. It's all small stuff. It's just a
reminder like stuff happens and 95% of stuff that happens isn't
really a big deal. You know, on occasion you lose a
loved one or someone, there's an accident. But even then, like,
what are you going to do? You have to be calm during
chaos. So, yeah, I sent that
book to a lot of people.
Okay, so we've talked about career a lot.
I do
know that you're a family man, husband and father. So
for anybody that's becoming a father or anybody becoming a
husband, what's your best piece of advice for
any first time fathers or first time husbands?
First time father, I'll take that. I think something my wife and
I did a great job of and we are huge, huge believers in
quantity of time with kids. That's we just just that safety
of the kids when they're real little just kind of knowing that
you as a parent, you're always around,
you're always there. I think it's incredibly important.
That's the first thing that comes to mind is just quantity versus quality. And then
first time husband, it's hard. So the tip I would give is obviously all the basics,
complete love and respect for your spouse. But I think it's really important if you're a hammer and you actually go to an office and work most days before you get home, maybe pulling
over, taking a deep breath and remembering that, all right, good day, bad day at work, it's time to pay attention and be a partner to your spouse when you walk in those doors.
Okay, so I'm going to give you a tip.
I think you have to be authentic, obviously.
And I'm not an affectionate person, except
for with three people in the entire world.
I'm not a guy that hugs guys or girls, but I think it's really, really important
to be affectionate with your kids and your spouse and sadly, a lot of people aren't.
And then I think it's really, really important as
well, if you're silly, be silly with your kids.
If you're serious, you have to be serious with people, especially if it's
a non gaps model and then where will the kids be oh my God.
I'm a little spill-song, this is in me
with my kids.
And getting me to the pink one is like going to an early school festival and I just remember like, oh Kevin and I
are kids, I don't remember, it's like a marathon, dólares and yeah, and it's not only kids andеди at every day, they're even little kids.
try and add a little humor and find common interests.
You know, my son and
I, we were all into reading.
We'd go on reading trips sometimes.
Sometimes we'd let my daughter and I
would do more shopping trips.
Obviously you have plenty of experience in your career,
but is there one habit, it could be one habit
or multiple habits that you keep every single day,
whether it was when you were actively working heavily
in your career when you were younger,
or even to this day, that helps you become successful?
I'm working harder now than I ever have,
but it doesn't feel like work
because surrounded by a bunch of energetic, youthful
hammers.
So I start off every day with a triple espresso
in my parlor, which is just a chair,
but I call it my parlor.
And I do a few minutes of meditation
and I literally for 30 seconds to five minutes,
just gratitude towards my family,
towards I get to work today.
I get to live in Austin, Texas.
I'm out of that terrible weather in Chicago.
Every morning I started off with the espresso
and some form of meditation,
which a lot of people do.
It works.
I've been doing it for years.
I feel like a lot of people mentioned meditation
and gratitude stuff, but there's so many people out there
that are thinking like, oh, meditation, gratitude, whatever.
It's, is it overlooked in a way?
Like it really works.
To me, the espresso is the best part.
Gratitude is I think pretty easy.
Like just, you know, everyone
has stuff to be thankful for.
So that's pretty easy.
And then meditation, I do a three minute meditation
or sometimes an eight and 90% of the time
I'm thinking about business or my family
for 94% of the meditation, I'm thinking about business.
And then I'm thinking about my
family for 94% of the meditation.
I don't know.
But to me, it's a habit
and I feel good when I'm done.
So my next question for you is,
what do you think is the biggest mindset change
that people need in order to become a multimillionaire?
I think they need to, A,
actually come up with a plan
and then they need to have the tenacity
and the wherewithal to execute on that plan.
It's, it's hard.
So you come up with an idea
and you come up with a plan,
which a lot of people don't
really come up with a plan.
And then you just gotta stick with it.
A lot of people give up, I
think, a day, a week, a month
before their business was gonna fricking go to the moon.
But for you personally, you know, a lot of people,
they find a lack of motivation
or a lack of desire for success.
What is your driving factor for success for you?
So I think when I was younger,
I was just trying to make a living.
Then I wanted to be
ultra successful and make more money
and provide more for my family.
I think now I'm kind of the second mountain.
This is kind of my final mountain, if you will.
My partner and I joined a
group called the Mountain of Success.
We joined Virtus, you know,
three and a half years ago
with a few other folks on our team.
And now it's about legacy.
We've quadrupled in three years
and I can't even imagine where they're gonna be
and you know, where we're gonna be in five years
and in 10, 15, 20 years.
So it's legacy having a small impact
on a bunch of guys and girls your age
who are on their way to
making millions and millions of dollars.
So hopefully they remember, you know,
some little piece of advice I gave them
to help them be more successful
professionally and personally.
Basically, a lot of people might define success
in different ways.
How do you define success?
First and foremost, it's having a happy family life.
That's the foundation to everything.
And I am beyond lucky that I have it.
So I'm the greatest wife in the world
and two phenomenal kids and a great son-in-law.
So that's first and foremost.
And then right behind it is financial freedom.
Being able to take a deep breath,
not having to worry about paying the bills.
Don't have to go to work.
If they turn into bad people,
you can just leave and get another job
or start your own.
To me, that success, you know,
sprinkled in with a handful of good friends.
If you had three guiding principles
for the next generation,
what would those three principles be?
Try and be a hammer.
So work hard, be a really good teammate,
and get a lot of time alone.
Spend time alone, thinking, reflecting, appreciating life.
I just want to talk
about two of those real quick,
but I guess what is the significance
of having that alone time with yourself?
A lot of people, they're terrified of being lonely.
They're terrified of being by themselves.
But like, what would you say
is the importance of that?
I think it's just so important to,
on the business side, to decompress,
get away from your phone, get away from your computer.
You know, our firm, we're doing that this month.
We're spending a lot of time trying to get away
and reflect on the year and plan for next year.
Lock yourself in a room somewhere
where no one's going to disturb you.
Go to, you know, our CEO's going to, you know,
a farm for eight hours and locking themselves up there
just to get away and think and reflect.
And I also believe alone time is when
get hit with that random thought.
And if the business is not going great,
then I don't know what to do.
I think if you're a leader in that,
you're going to be the first person
to get out of your business.
You're going to be the first person
to get out of that trap
of how to make your business better.
If your bank account hits zero tomorrow,
what would be the first action that you would take
to kind of build your empire back?
I would get back into full-time sales
because I know I could still hustle and out-hustle people
and outwork them and get some commission checks quickly.
And with those commission checks,
you know, we talked about, like,
putting money in real estate I think is
really smart. I've also always put money in private
companies so private equity or if you have friends
or people you know that are starting companies and
you can get invest in those and then
maybe investing in your hobby whether it's like
collecting cars or baseball cards or something like that.
I've seen a lot of people that end up
turning their hobby into something that becomes
financially successful. So if you were to start
a new company tomorrow what resources would
you grab and what company would you start?
What resources would I grab? So I'm old
enough and I know enough people now where
if I had that incredible idea I'm confident I
could raise the money so that wouldn't be hard.
The idea I think I would probably do and I've
kind of been keeping in my back pocket for retirement.
I would start a company that taught people how
to be better parents. I've just always been fascinated
that I think there's parenting in in general is subpar
and I think my wife and I have made it our
best. I think that's a great idea. I think that's
a great idea. I think that's a great idea. I think
that's a great idea. I think that's a great idea.
I think that's a great idea. I think that's a great
idea. I think that's a great idea. I think that's
a great idea. I think that's a great idea. I think
mission and I think we're pretty good at it. We've
asked you a lot of questions today so thank you
so much for your time and just your
your mentorship and impact for some of these questions
but I did want to ask just to wrap up
the video how do you want to be remembered by?
I've thought about that before and I
think it's uh besides being an honorable hard-working
incredible husband and father I would say authentic
just real. I tell it like it is
sometimes that's good sometimes it's not
but uh just a nice authentic family
man who also uh kicks some fucking ass in business.
I love that. Guys that kind of wraps up episode
eight of 10 questions. Mike thank you so much.
I did want to get into your current company Virtus
uh kind of what you guys are doing
there if there's anything that you want to tell
the audience kind of about Virtus and what you
guys got going on. Yeah so our industry is uh
male pale and stale uh Virtus
Insurance headquartered Kansas City. We have offices
Fort Collins Colorado, Chicago, St. Louis, Austin,
Fort Worth and Memphis Tennessee. We're over 100
people. We have offices in Fort Collins Colorado,
Chicago, St. Louis, Austin, Fort Worth and Memphis.
We have offices in Fort Collins Colorado,
And if you're stuck in a sales position or a service position and it's with a bunch of people my age or older and it's slow and boring we are the antithesis. We are
shaking up the tired industry. Incredibly young, energetic, specialized. It's a game changer. So if you're bored and you want to have unlimited income potential and joy in your job track me down. Thank you.
Thanks guys. Make sure to like and subscribe and comment down below what
answer was your favorite and which question that Mike answered for us. Thanks guys.
Thank you so much.
Thank you so much for
giving your insight and your success.
Whew.
Do we want to reshoot this?
Yeah I'll put Scott away.
Yeah let's just reshoot it real quick.